<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immunant, Inc</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Immunant, Inc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Immunant, Inc.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitfields Forever: Why we need a C-compatible Rust Crate</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/01/bitfields/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/01/bitfields/</guid>
      <description>What Are Bitfields? The C programming language was a product of a time where it was extremely important to use as little space as possible. Memory was generally much more limited than it is today. Naturally, bitfields were one attempt to reduce memory usage. However, bitfields aren&amp;rsquo;t just a relic of the yesteryear of computer programming, sitting atop a shelf collecting dust. They&amp;rsquo;re still used today! Some domains, like embedded hardware, still require minimal memory footprints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating Quake 3 into Rust</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/01/quake3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/01/quake3/</guid>
      <description>The Rust-loving team at Immunant has been hard at work on C2Rust, a migration framework that takes the drudgery out of migrating to Rust. Our goal is to make safety improvements to the translated Rust automatically where we can, and help the programmer do the same where we cannot. First, however, we have to build a rock-solid translator that gets people up and running in Rust. Testing on small CLI programs gets old eventually, so we decided to try translating Quake 3 into Rust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source Code Linking: Merging C Headers into Rust Modules</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/12/header_merging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/12/header_merging/</guid>
      <description>Producing readable, idiomatic Rust code is a major goal of C2Rust, our project to accelerate migration of C code into Rust. One hurdle we faced is the mismatch between C headers and the Rust module system. C and Rust are similar in many ways: they&amp;rsquo;re both performance oriented languages with explicit memory management and full control over every aspect of the system. Rust&amp;rsquo;s module system is a huge improvement over C header files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust 2020: Lessons learned by transpiling C to Rust</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/11/rust2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/11/rust2020/</guid>
      <description>The C2Rust project is all about translating C code into an equivalent, drop-in ABI-compatible Rust implementation. (Read our C2Rust introductory blog post here.) Along the way we&amp;rsquo;ve uncovered some dark corners of C as it&amp;rsquo;s written in practice, and found places where Rust can&amp;rsquo;t quite replicate the same code with the same ABI. This is the story of those dark corners and the areas we think Rust needs to improve to be fully FFI compatible with C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved C Variadics in Rust and C2Rust</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/09/variadics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/09/variadics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to C Variadics The C language provides a special class of functions called variadic functions that can be called with a variable number of arguments. The declaration of a variadic function ends with an ellipsis, e.g.:
void variadic_function(int x, ...);  Variadic functions can be called with any number of arguments in place of the ellipsis (including none at all).
The C runtime provides a set of helper macros that developers use to retrieve the values of the variadic arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to C2Rust</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/08/introduction-to-c2rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/08/introduction-to-c2rust/</guid>
      <description>We believe that software should be both fast and safe. Languages like C and C++ deliver blazingly fast performance but are pretty much impossible to use safely. Software mitigations built into the operating system make exploitation of buggy code much harder but attackers are amazing at finding ways to bypass new defenses. What we really need is a way to eliminate the source of memory corruption bugs. Rust delivers on speed and interoperability while making memory safety the default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description> Name:   Email:   Message:   Send Message   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Message Sent</title>
      <link>/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/thanks/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for reaching out; we&amp;rsquo;ll be in touch shortly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing for Security</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/09/multicompiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/09/multicompiler/</guid>
      <description>It is obviously very bad if everybody used the same password. It is also bad when one person reuses the same password across sites. Luckily, we have password managers that can generate unique, random passwords for each site. It is no less of a problem when everybody runs the same software for the following reason: When a software flaw is found, we want every installation of the program to be different enough that the same malicious input cannot compromise multiple users (but not so different that users notice).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Migration</title>
      <link>/migrating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/migrating/</guid>
      <description>The risks of memory safety bugs are well understood. Even expert developers struggle to correctly use C/C++. In the best case scenario, the development process is augmented by an array of bug finding tools such as fuzzers and static analyzers. Even so, we know that memory safety bugs invariably make it into the released code where they will be found by attackers.
For instance, Microsoft reported that over the last 12 years, 70% of Microsoft security patches address memory safety bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardening and Exploit Mitigation</title>
      <link>/mitigating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mitigating/</guid>
      <description>Need to process untrusted inputs with C/C++? Oftentimes, security best practices do not get implemented; limited resources causes things to slip through the cracks. Our expert security engineers work alongside your team to measurably increase the security of your product. Whether you rely on software developed in house or third party/open source libraries, we will help you assess your current security posture and deploy additional software hardening techniques without degrading overall system performance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>