<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immunant, Inc</title>
    <link>//immunant.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Immunant, Inc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//immunant.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Positions</title>
      <link>//immunant.com/page/jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//immunant.com/page/jobs/</guid>
      <description>Full-Time Positions No open positions at the moment.
 -- Internships We accept applications for full-time, onsite paid internships. Duration must be three months or longer.
Applying Preference is given to candidates willing to relocate to Southern California. Remote work is not an option for applicants located outside of the US.
Employment is conditional on applicants selected for employment passing worldwide background checks. Immunant participates in E-verify.
Email your application to team [at] immunant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributor License Agreement</title>
      <link>//immunant.com/page/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 18:11:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//immunant.com/page/contribute/</guid>
      <description>If you are interested in contributing to Immunant&amp;rsquo;s open source projects, please complete, sign, and send us one of the following contributor license agreements. Send your signed copy to team [at] immunant.com.
 Contributor license agreement for individuals Contributor license agreement for entities  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing for Security</title>
      <link>//immunant.com/blog/2018/09/multicompiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//immunant.com/blog/2018/09/multicompiler/</guid>
      <description>It is obviously very bad if everybody used the same password. It is also bad when one person reuses the same password across sites. Luckily, we have password managers that can generate unique, random passwords for each site. It is no less of a problem when everybody runs the same software for the following reason: When a software flaw is found, we want every installation of the program to be different enough that the same malicious input cannot compromise multiple users (but not so different that users notice).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>